<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entity name="PAUPInfer" class="ptolemy.kernel.ComponentEntity">
<property name="entityId"  value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:472:1" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId"/>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Zhijie Guan, Alex Borchers</configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure><p>The PaupInfer actor is a CIPRES actor that invokes an external PAUP ("Phylogenic Analysis Using Parsimony") service and returns a generated phylogenetic tree, or an error if the service does not execute correctly.</p>

<p>To use the full suite of CIPRES actors, CIPRES software must be installed on the local system. The PAUPInfer actor also requires PAUP software, and must be used with the Initializer actor.</p>

<p>The actor generates a graphical interface that allows users to input information (e.g., a command or working directory) and pass the data to the PAUP application. Once the application has been contacted and has processed the input, the actor returns the generated results, or an error if the application does not execute correctly. </p>

<p>If the PAUP service returns correctly, the result of the execution will be output and written to a file in Nexus format. </p>

<p>The actor can also be used to monitor error words in the results. Whenever the actor identifies any of the user-specified error words, it will notify the user and ask for further instructions.</p>

<p>PAUP (Phylogenic Analysis Using Parsimony) is a tool used to infer phylogenetic relationships. For more information about PAUP, see http://paup.csit.fsu.edu/</p>

<p>The CIPRES (Cyberinfrastructure for Phylogenetic Research) project works to enable large-scale phylogenetic reconstructions that facilitate analyses of datasets containing large numbers of bio molecular sequences. For more information about CIPRES, see http://www.phylo.org/</p></configure></property>
<property name="port:standardError" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the standard error stream of the execution.</configure></property>
<property name="port:inputParameterValue" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that accepts the name of an input file. Input files should contain the data to be analyzed, and may be in NEXUS or tab-delimited format. For a complete list of supported file types, see http://paup.csit.fsu.edu/paupfaq/faq.html.</configure></property>
<property name="port:outputParameterValue" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the name of the output results file. Output files are written in Nexus format.</configure></property>
<property name="port:inputParameterName" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that accepts the name of the input (usually &quot;infile&quot;).</configure></property>
<property name="port:exitCode" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the exit code of the execution.</configure></property>
<property name="port:standardOutput" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the results of the execution.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:command" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure> The path to the command file. Alternatively, a command file can be generated and passed to the actor via the user interface generated by the GUIGen XML File. This is an advanced parameter used mainly by programmers.</configure></property>

<property name="prop:uiXMLFile" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The GUIGen XML file path and name. GUIGen XML files generate a flexible user interface that can be used to input and pass commands to the CIPRES application.This is an advanced parameter used mainly by programmers. </configure></property>
<property name="prop:outputFile" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The standard output file path (e.g., C:\Documents and Settings\Myself\results.log). </configure></property>
<property name="prop:errorFile" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The standard error file path (e.g., C:\Documents and Settings\Myself\error.log). </configure></property>
<property name="prop:workingDirectory" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The working directory of the external CIPRES program.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:parameterForOutput" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The parameter to return. Usually the parameter is "outfile"</configure></property>
<property name="prop:paupCmdFile " class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The name of the PAUP command file.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:iterations" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>The number of times the PAUP program should iterate.</configure></property>
<property name="prop:monitoredErrorWords" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Words to monitor. Whenever the actor identifies any of the specified error words, it will notify the user and ask for further instructions.</configure></property>

</property><property name="class" value="org.cipres.kepler.PAUPInfer" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute">
  <property name="id" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:class:1210:1" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute"/>
</property>
<property name="semanticType00" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#CIPResActor" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType"/>
<property name="semanticType11" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:4:1#CIPRes" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType"/>
</entity>
