<?xml version="1.0"?>
<entity name="RecIDCM3" class="ptolemy.kernel.ComponentEntity">
<property name="entityId"  value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:actor:458:1" class="org.kepler.moml.NamedObjId"/>
<property name="KeplerDocumentation" class="ptolemy.vergil.basic.KeplerDocumentationAttribute">
<property name="description" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="author" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>Zhijie Guan </configure></property>
<property name="version" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>null</configure></property>
<property name="userLevelDocumentation" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure><p>The RecIDCM3 actor implements a fast algorithmic technique for reconstructing phylogenetic trees. The actor, which invokes a CIPRES CORBA service to generate its results, accepts a data matrix and a phylogenetic tree, and outputs an inferred tree. </p>

<p>CORBA services, much like Web services, are computer programs that run on a remote host and communicate using a standardized protocol that allows them to interoperate. CIPRES CORBA services are specifically designed to help analyze phylogenetic data sets.</p>

<p>To use the full suite of CIPRES actors, CIPRES software must be installed on the local system. The RecIDCM3 actor must also be used with the Initializer actor, which connects to the registry of CORBA services used by the CIPRES actors.</p> 

<p>The actor's input values--the data matrix and tree--can be generated by the PhyloDataReader actor, which reads a Nexus file and outputs the data in a form that can be readily used by the RecIDCM3 actor.</p>

<p>The RecIDCM3 service implements the Recursive, Iterative, DCM3 (Disk Coverage Method) algorithm. For more information about RecIDCM3, see http://www.cs.njit.edu/~usman/RecIDCM3.html </p>

<p>The CIPRES (Cyberinfrastructure for Phylogenetic Research) project works to enable large-scale phylogenetic reconstructions that facilitate analyses of datasets containing large numbers of bio molecular sequences. For more information about CIPRES, see http://www.phylo.org/</p></configure></property>
<property name="port:inputTree" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that accepts a CIPRES tree data structure consisting of the tree name, tree score, leaf set, and/or Newick. The tree can be generated by the PhyloDataReader actor, which reads Nexus files and outputs data in a format that CIPRES actors can readily use. The specified tree is used as the initial tree for the RecIDCM3 algorithm.</configure></property>
<property name="port:inputDataMatrix" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An input port that accepts a matrix containing character information about the analyzed taxa. The data matrix can be generated by the PhyloDataReader actor, which reads Nexus files and outputs data in a format that CIPRES actors can readily use.</configure></property>
<property name="port:outputTree" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.ConfigurableAttribute"><configure>An output port that broadcasts the inferred tree in Nexus format.</configure></property>
</property><property name="class" value="org.cipres.kepler.RecIDCM3" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute">
  <property name="id" value="urn:lsid:kepler-project.org:class:1210:1" class="ptolemy.kernel.util.StringAttribute"/>
</property>
<property name="semanticType00" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:1:1#CIPResActor" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType"/>
<property name="semanticType11" value="urn:lsid:localhost:onto:4:1#CIPRes" class="org.kepler.sms.SemanticType"/>
</entity>
